The issue is which people don't
understand is once you start leaning
into this stuff, your actual constraint
is still the same, [music] which is
there is more demand. And last month I
spent 11 grand on top [music] of my Mac
subscription. This is what people don't
understand. It's almost well, it is
infinite demand.
>> It's infinite demand. And the more you
use it, the more it [music] fills up.
And that's why anyone who thinks that
they're going to get free time from AI,
it's the opposite. My time is completely
saturated. Token 2049 [music] Singapore,
the world's largest crypto event,
returns to Marina Bay Sands on the 7th
of 8th of October. On stage will be
myself, Jeff Yan from Hyperlquid, Shane
Copam from Poly Market, and the Real
Vision community gets 10% off tickets.
Claim yours using the link below. See
you there. Hi, I'm Ral Pal and welcome
to my show, The Journeyman. The
journeyman as you know by now is where
we travel to that nexus of understanding
of macro crypto and the exponential age
of technology.
About once a quarter I always have a
fantastic conversation with a very good
friend of mine Jordi Vissa. Jordi and I
same background the hedge fund world
investment banks and we both leapt into
the world of crypto and technology and
overlay it with our macro thinking. It's
always a great conversation. I'm sure
you're going to enjoy it. But before we
get to [music] today's show, this
episode is brought to you by Pith. Pith
Network is the fastest growing financial
data [music] company today. Trusted by
Fidelity Investments, the US Department
of Commerce, Revolute, [music] Calshi,
Jane Street, Coinbase, and many more.
They provide realtime market data across
3,000 equities, commodities, crypto, FX,
rates, and more. They're the first and
largest provider of 247 financial
indices [music] and offer the widest
array of market data for the lowest
cost. Go to pith.network network to take
advantage of their free trial. Join me,
Ral Pal, as I go on a journey of
discovery through the macro, crypto, and
exponential age landscapes. In the
journey, man, I talk to the smartest
people in the world so we can all become
smarter together.
Jord Vissa, how the devil are you,
>> Raul? I'm great. How you doing?
>> Good. take my glasses off for you.
>> Just um Yeah, I had surgery. I've got
rid of my glasses finally. I had
>> I had You had laser surgery cuz I'm an
old man and uh I can now see. It's
amazing.
>> Yeah, I had I had Lasix surgery I don't
know if it's maybe 12 years ago now. It
was great for the first five years and
then you know you need readers anyway.
So
>> yeah, exactly. It's uh but it's amazing
the technology, right? It's just
amazing. You just get that done.
>> So, what's happening with you? What's on
your mind right now?
>> I always love our chats because I have
no idea where they're going to go. We
just
>> go somewhere.
>> Well, rather than start with um with
crypto and and AI, um let's let's talk
bonds. Um
>> yeah. Okay. Interesting.
>> Where where my brain is, I I I I
literally believe this is the most
the biggest marketing scam I've ever
seen in terms of people so fixated on
this quote unquote collapse in bonds
around the globe on 30-year yields. And
I think this is a social media thing
more than than anything. And it it only
hit me when someone said something to me
and said, "Have you looked at the charts
of US bonds?" And I went, "Well, yeah. I
look at the total return of them all the
time and they're down 3% year-to date
for the 20 plus ETF. uh this is not a
big move but because you have these
charts showing well this is the highest
yield in the last 20 years and I I got
into a discussion recently with someone
we both know and they said how are you
not concerned about this uh with regards
to AI and the capital buildout and I've
heard you talk about some of this stuff
and I said when did it become this thing
where when PMIs around the globe are are
are going higher when profits are are
not only soaring But they're at levels
almost unprecedented. But they are
unprecedented when you put the fact that
we're not hiring anyone, that employment
is barely growing and we're at
recessionary type hiring levels. Profit
margins are expanding. Don't you think
you might be missing something? And oh,
by the way, if you would have sold the
NEI last May when they hit their highs
in 30-year yields, you'd be down 70% or
missing 70%. So that's where my head is
right now is I think this this bond
yield panic that everyone has that I
think Ray Dalio and everyone's gone in
and then you know the op-ed from Duck I
think it just has a a big focus and can
Bessant actually keep this in check when
the reality is we've been through enough
cycles that yields going higher is
probably going to mean a lot of weaker
places companies go out of business but
that was going to happen with AI anyway
so I don't view this as a negative thing
I view it as a positive positive.
>> Yeah, I mean I just a I think Besson's
made it pretty clear that
he need I mean really it's a supply
issue because you've got the AI guy, you
know, the hyperscalers now issuing and
the government issuing and you basically
need a weaker dollar for the foreign
central banks to buy bonds. And he's
gone over to Japan and he's gone to
China and he's gone to South Korea and
he's gone to the UAE. He's sorted out
swap lines and I think he's got an
agreement with the Chinese is look we'll
try and lower the dollar and then the
interview in the yen. So you know he's a
macro guy. We've known him for a long
time and you know what he's up to and
then he's gone around he's a bond
salesman so he has to go around and find
a place for these bonds and so I just
think that yeah they're going to be
pretty anchored in the end but what
everybody needs is a steeper yield
curve. So they kind of do need the Walsh
part of the equation and I think Walsh
is playing the game which is he's got to
sound credible and tight but he knows
and Bessant keeps saying the inflation
numbers are going to be weaker than
expected and productivity is going to be
stronger and you know Bessant's saying
things like I'm armed with inside
information and so you kind of feel that
wherever the rates are um we're kind of
in the range where they should unlikely
to go higher. You know, I look at demark
a lot as indicators. They're stacking up
on the weeklies, dailies, monthlies.
It's very close to that reversal when
it's peak fear. Um, and it doesn't do
much damage to most people. As you said,
there is an old economy that is heavily
in debt and over time that's going to
get into trouble. There's a lot of these
credit funds and all of that stuff that
needs clearing at some point. I don't
think it clears now. I think it clears
at some at some point down the road from
the the nexus of both AI and this and
and yield. So I kind of still are
looking for the weaker dollar and a
steeper yield curve and just see how it
goes from there. And that to to your
Japan point is
that's exactly what Japan did is they
engineered a steep yield curve and guess
what? The bank started lending. If
you're going to if we're going to
finance this massive capex voom boom,
you need the banks to be lending. It's
as simple as that. And then you just
steep a yield curve at whatever it is 40
basis points. It's just not enough.
>> And again, if if if I was worried about
things, I'd be looking at how bank
stocks are trading around the globe. And
bank stocks around the globe are up, you
know, 30% year-over-year. So, you know,
I'm a big believer and you know, in when
people talk about the fact that the
market is a discounting uh mechanism,
I've always subscribed to that and I
believe the rate of change of the stock
prices would tell you the same way that
earnings and profit margins should mean
revert. If we're heading into a problem,
you should see hiring going through. But
if you're not hiring anyone and revenues
are growing and you have a fiscal
deficit and you have all this spending
happening from the private sector, you
know, we can all get worried. Um, but I
I just don't see it as something there.
I I want to bring something up to you
because I've been
>> just one side just to go back on that.
I'm not sure if it was you who mentioned
it or somebody else that if you want
evidence of productivity, it's the point
you're exactly raising. Record earnings
and low employment. And that's I mean
that is your answer. The other thing on
productivity I just want to mention is I
wrote a whole article in GMI about
Amazon and used Amazon as an example of
what the global economy would look like
if they adopted AI and robotics to its
core. Right? Because that's what
Amazon's done since over the last eight
years or so. They've completely turned
into a productivity machine where their
kind of earnings are now going up, their
margins are going up because they've
employed this technology and it's like
that's proof of what the world will look
like when people catch up. Amazon's just
a pioneer.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I I I heard you mention
that and I don't remember which
interview or which thing it I think you
were actually talking to someone and
then you brought it up and it reminded
me of you know I went out to Silicon
Valley to kind of migrate away from the
traditional macro way I'd approach
things back in 2013 and the reason was
this collision between two things. One
was the debtfilled let's just grow at
any pace Chinese. I I viewed them as the
caboose of this kind of debtfueled
world. They built out all the cities and
I realized that's it. They've got a
demographic issue just like the Western
world. They have a debt problem that
they're going to have to basically find
a way to burn off over time. And I went
out to Silicon Valley because Amazon
didn't make any sense to me in 2013. I
didn't understand how a company could
trade at an infinity PE and really smart
people were convincing me that it was
you you're not getting it. So, I had to
go there and that changed my mind. and I
went to Singularity University and
that's the the the beginning stage of me
believing that where we are now there's
a time mismatch and I really do believe
this the reason the Nikai thing is so
important to me so May of last year the
NE the 30-year yields and the JGB's
break through alltime highs if you go
search in Grock and you say show me all
the the posts that came out in X around
the peak of this you'll get a zero hedge
one saying the world is going to blow up
this is the biggest thing
>> the yen carry trade the carry trade all
this stuff and here we are um you know
18 months later and the Nikkei is off
the highs. So this is not me saying at
the peak. This is it's still up 70% from
that point. And the reason it's
important is I really do believe we have
one side of the equation that's moving
at exponential speed and then we have
all of the old legacy world even the
debt which is based on human speed. And
the problem is if you're growing on one
side so fast, if you're able to grow
earnings but not hire people, GDP
doesn't know how to capture that yet. We
don't have a way to capture that. How
are we growing earnings and revenue so
fast and not hiring anyone? And and if
people say, "Well, we're hiring some
people demographics." If you strip out
health care, which will be the last of
the things that will be greatly impacted
by AI, there's no hiring and there
hasn't been any hiring for 20 months
now. So the question comes in profit
margins are definitely a way to look at
it. But I think this mismatch between
something moving so fast that you can't
comprehend what ARR means in anthropic
and open AAI and cursor before it. We've
never seen these types of movements. And
then on the other side, oh, debt's up
again. We're up another trillion
dollars, but it's growing at a pace far
slower than the exponential side. And
that's where I think the mismatch is.
>> And what about
the old way we used to look at bonds was
just nominal GDP. So maybe, you know,
how I'm thinking about this is yes, you
know, financial repression means they
want to keep bond yields below nominal
GDP. Fine. Um, but they should have a
tendency to rise and we'll probably swap
out the inflation component for the
productivity component. That's kind of
my working roadmap.
>> Yeah. And you you know this uh as well
as I do, but historically basically
before 1997, Treasury yields, 10ear
yields usually traded about 200 basis
points above nominal GDP. So nominal GDP
right now is at 6% in the US
year-over-year, six and change. So
theoretically, using the pre97 time, we
should be up at 8 1/2%. Well, we're not
up at 8 and 1/2, we're 4 and 3/4. So
we're already trading below. Now this
started that switch off started in 1997.
Now that was the Asian financial crisis
which was the original cause. But that
was also when we started this whole okay
the demographic shift. The the debt is
now increasing. And at the same time
that was really when the internet
started to become an investable thing.
And all of those things kind of line up.
And that's where I think everyone's just
getting way over their skis on looking
at the bond market and believing that AI
can't continue to grow. And I know you
know this, but most people don't. The
interest cost for them, whether they pay
6%, 8%, 9%, it doesn't change their
profits on their business. This is such
a small.
>> In fact, profits went up for most of the
hyperscalers because they have cash. Now
they don't have as much cash, but yeah,
they made a fortune from it.
>> Yeah. And
>> that's the whole of Japan, by the way.
the whole of Japan, every household
>> is a saver. So, you're giving them extra
money and which people don't realize.
>> Yeah. And so inflation will stay above
the 2%. It will freak people out. But I
view this as an academic argument. I
just think people are using their
history books. They're using a time
where if the consumers of the world, the
growers of the world were human beings,
that's one thing. But we have billions
of AI agents over the next 12 months.
Billions. And now with Gac and the
ability to just create I mean I've
created more AI agents in the past
whatever it's been 10 days since I
started using it. I can't stop coming up
with ideas. So if you look at it now I'm
running into the problem a lot of people
are which is I have 75 agents and I I
got to make sure that I remember who's
who. That's my biggest issue. So we're
just
>> Yeah. But I had to create a even on my
Claude I had to create a COO to manage
all of my agents cuz in the full-time
[\h__\h] job because they keep breaking
or disappearing or whatever. So, I've
got that and then I'm using the Grock
one and I'm already at like six Asians.
I only started three days ago. It's
insane. The the issue is which people
don't understand is once you start
leaning into this stuff, your actual
constraint is still the same, which is
there is more demand. And what happened
to me is like I started having to pay
for Fable 5 and it went from like a
couple of grand and last month I spent
11 grand on top of my Mac subscription.
I'm like this is what people don't
understand. It's almost well it is
infinite demand.
>> It it it's infinite demand and the more
you use it the more it fills up. And
that's why um anyone who thinks that if
they're still working in any kind of way
that they're going to get free free time
from AI, it's the opposite. Um my time
is completely saturated. It's filled.
It's taken away from watching sports, a
lot of other things. But it just shows
how much I like learning, how much I
like being on top of what's going on.
And I'm starting to spend all of my time
on tokenization. Um, I've been asked by
again a lot of people we know on the
macro side because I do these weekly
videos and I've been starting to migrate
more towards the importance of
tokenization in in a broader scale. Um,
I've never had more fun learning a topic
and connecting it back to the world that
we grew up in and the impact that it's
going to have. And especially as we're
seeing countries start to go through the
same race for different reasons that
China and the US are in AI, Japan's
realizing that if they don't adopt the
blockchain for all of their assets
quickly, their capital markets will
worsen. And capital markets are now
becoming one of the topics that everyone
cares about because we need to raise
money. So the depth of the markets to
take capital, the democratization of
everyone being able to invest has become
more important. So tokenization becomes
a very important solution to the
problems we're having with the 10ear
yield. Um it really is, hey, I want to
go raise debt. Well, let's pocket this
in something where 8 billion people can
buy it as opposed to just isolated to a
few few places even though they have a
lot of money. So, I think tokenization
and this whole um ability to learn about
what's going on and connect it back. I
I'm I'm having the best time with this.
>> What do you think happens with the asset
management complex? Cuz let's say debt,
okay, let's say corporate debt. So
corporate debt tends to get aggregated
into funds that then get bought by
pension plans
um maybe in a 401k but rarely um because
they they tend to be um only available
to accredited investors and that kind of
stuff. So what happens to all of those
people in that chain? They have to adapt
or die, right?
>> They have to adapt or die. It's
deflationary obviously. Um because the
one thing about
the industry of asset management is and
we all know this we make returns we
don't make things and those returns
are judged by someone on whether they
can understand them because if if they
did it based on true historical returns
then Bitcoin would be much higher than
it is today because it's been the best
performing asset over the last 15 years.
If it was a hedge fund and it had a
human being describing what it did and
you had the same returns as Bitcoin, it
would be many, many trillions of dollars
more than it is today. But because it's
a black box, there's no story. There's
no narrative. Human beings have a hard
time. The one thing about asset
management is that younger people are
very comfortable not having a human
being deal with them. And so the way
that I viewed this is it will take some
time, but this is a massive disruption
to asset managers. And let me break it
into two parts. The one part you're
saying is if you believe in
diversification, if you believe that by
investing in 10,000 assets that are
possibly yielding between 8 and 10%. The
diversification of choosing
things that get paid off movie royalties
that get paid. Think about every single
thing you can and you diversify and
everyone you're choosing from is
returning 8 to 10% with a good sharp
ratio, but they're completely
uncorrelated. You are by definition
creating a better return stream that
will have no volatility. you're
basically replicating what the
millenniums and the citadels have been
able to do over time. And so I think
that that's the thing people are missing
is it might take a little time, but
eventually the diversification
opportunities, the instant ability to
find this many strategies and find a
thousand of them because when you meet a
pension fund, their biggest issue is
well I I can't find a manager that can
handle the money that I have and still
generate the returns. Well, if you can
invest in every single person in the
Philippines and everything like that
through a democratization, you can
create an 8 to 10% return stream with a
tuval and all of a sudden now you have
all this money. But the other thing,
Raul, and I think this is the most
important thing for you and I, we grew
up and we've traded markets overnight
and as macro people, it's very tiring.
It's a young person's business.
[laughter]
>> Oh, Japan moved. I got
>> I'm still scarred by [\h__\h] Tokyo in
the middle of the night. dollar yen
blowing up. He's like, "Oh god, you're
woken up." Yeah, that's why I laughed.
[laughter]
>> So, and and again, I remember that too,
like you you go to bed hoping the phone
doesn't ring, hoping nothing happens.
Well, think about when it's 247 starting
this year, and it already has started
with Iran hyperlquid, with um the SpaceX
IPO. Like I don't think people realize
it is not a human being's game to have
24/7 trading and what that is going to
mean for stop- losses, emotional
decisions, no sleep. So I just think the
disruption is going to come from human
beings realizing they can't play a game
that the that the bots can play better.
>> And how I look at it like a macro level
and um interesting to hear your views on
this is let's take an asset management
firm, an aggregator firm like
Millennium. So what does Millennium do?
There's the mother ship which allocates
capital compliance, you know, all of the
operational functions and then you've
got a bunch of pods which is return
streams of which they're um you know
there's a quite large diversity. All of
those essentially become whether it's
individuals or individuals agents
and the mother ship doesn't need all the
the massive infrastructure because
everything's tokenized. So it it kind of
changes that entire asset management
game. And we could do that for
everything, a pension plan, everything,
not just a hedge fund. It's the same
thing. And it completely disrupts the
whole system and where the fees are
earned and who earns the fees and how it
acrs. as you said, it's it's
deflationary more than anything else
because the fees are just going to
collapse.
>> Yeah. And the great thing for let's use
Millennium and De Shaw and take ones
that are much more bot driven already
and then ones that are using technology
and AI with inside their business. And
let's just say um they're the perfect
places for the AI agents to basically
dis I don't want to say disrupt their
business, but they have a story to tell
and they have a black box. They don't
give you the details of every single
thing. They don't go through it. You're
in a long-term lockup. They have the
ability of kind of building out the
agentic side with inside, reducing their
cost structure dramatically.
>> Marshall Waste just announced that they
they've been doing this.
>> Yeah. And and I think they're the
natural places to basically do this.
They have the money to do it. So, they
already have the technology side. They
already have all the engineers. So, I
think they'll be the ones first that are
actually disrupting everything. They'll
be competing more with retail, but I
think you're going to see the rest of
the business kind of go through this.
It'll just happen, like you said before,
it's a merging of two worlds. It's the
human side merging with the bot side,
and it's going to happen together. And
the bigger places have the first
advantage because they can do it very
easily and very cheaply.
>> And what's weird is, you know, people
hear the term tokenization, but they
only get so far. Oh yes, equities are
going to go on chain or oh yes, I can
get rid of my shitty credit fund by
putting it on chain and selling it to,
you know, end customers because I' got
no buyers. But they don't realize how
disruptive this is because everything,
all funds will go on chain, people's
return streams will go on chain, AI
agents will go on chain, they all become
investable and it a velocity of capital
goes up violently. That's another thing.
>> Yeah. And so you and I have talked about
this before and I think we're both on
the same page as this. Um what I believe
tokenization will be a year from now is
a recognition by everyone that um what's
happening in the stock market right now.
So I use Nvidia as like the example. Uh
Nvidia has blown away earnings since
October of last year. But as of
yesterday's close and let's just say a
couple days after their most recent
earnings, the stock was effectively
unchanged from October. And when the
most recent earnings report came out,
they blew away numbers in a way we've
never seen before. Um, I mean, the
street was expecting 44% revenue growth
for next year and they said it's going
to be 70. And that was the company, I'm
sure, handcuffing this like they all do
to some degree. So, the stock hadn't
moved. And every earnings report that's
good now, if you were a trader in the
late 90s and even the early 2000s, if if
company beat by that much, you expect to
get rewarded for it. I don't think
that's happening anymore. And so I I
showed on my most recent video that if
you take Nvidia relative to the S&P,
it's basically up it's outperformed the
S&P by I think 40% over the prior two
years, 26 months. But there was one
corridor of four months where that
entire outperformance happened. The rest
of the 20 months it did nothing. And
what that tells me is if volumes and
velocity are going up, the toll
collectors are going to start making the
money. Essenth
of a basis point, a hundth of a basis
point, and this is where crypto fits in.
I don't think you can match up
fundamentals in terms of the narrative
with the performance anymore. more. And
so if you can't create alpha by just
saying this company's going to beat
earnings and this is going to go through
the way you could in the past, then I
think toll collectors are going to make
the money because it's just a lot of
spinning your wheels and no one really
making any money betting on this stuff.
You get paid as the house by the volume
and less about this. This is where I
think it's going over the next few
years.
>> Yeah, I think I'm a big believer that
almost everything will end up being a
marketplace. So you know even a platform
like real vision will become a
marketplace for you know investing in
people but then at a bigger level if you
think what do the agents consume? Well
they obviously consume
energy and compute.
>> Mhm.
>> Um but the other thing they consume and
people haven't put this two and two
together is data.
They need more and more data over time.
And so that means that an agent-driven
data marketplace is probably the biggest
marketplace that will ever exist because
all information has to be absorbed into
the beast for it to grow from a AGI to
ASI, right? There's you have to and so
it's going to suck in every single piece
of information that is possibly has some
informationational value and they'll
trade at different prices and who gets
the monopoly on the data, who doesn't,
and that'll all be a hidden market. We
won't even see it. There's no prices on
a screen. It just happens.
>> Yeah. Luckily for all of us, um it'll
take such a long time to get to that
because of the video side, meaning the
ability of taking in everything that we
see and comprehend, which is far more
data than the actual data in a computer
screen. We're just not at the we're not
at the data center side of the the video
side. We don't have pure humanoids
ability to navigate through everything
in the street. And it's going to take a
lot of data. that's going to take a lot
more compute. Only reason I bring it up
is um I have started to recognize that
the merging of these two if it wasn't
for the compute shortage that we have
right now relative to the capabilities
and the acceleration of the intelligence
uh it would be a much more dystopian
world. I'm becoming less worried about
the world merging together because of
the friction of politics, because of the
friction of human beings, because of the
bottleneck frictions of physics. All of
these things are actually making it more
comfortable for me that we won't get to
the point of AGI happening too fast.
It'll happen. It probably already has
happened depending on or it already has
happened depending on your definition.
But the merging of the worlds of humans
in this, it's giving us enough time to
actually think about it and go through
the thought process while we're worrying
about how it's going to play out. Uh and
so I'm I'm getting more comfortable that
the frictions are good, not bad.
>> Yeah, I agree. and we're seeing the the
rise of world models versus LLMs and I
think the whole thing converges
>> but you know I'm here in Napa I've
rented a Tesla and I haven't actually
driven once I touch the pedal it just
drives you around you know so a lot of
it's here already and people don't
realize it what Google's been able to
train off video itself there's a lot
there and then you're seeing there was
yesterday a I think it was called Atlas
did you see that there's a video
generation model I mean these are wild
now. You cannot tell what's film, what's
not film.
>> So, it's you can see all the component
parts are just
>> blending together. But you say, as you
say, I mean, it's a lot of compute and
we just don't have it.
>> Yeah, we don't have it. And that's why
from an investable standpoint, we're
we're we're never we're not going to get
to the point that we can overbuild
because we're just I mean, we might
short term we could over buy things and
we could have inventories grow up, but
we're we're not going to use all the
compute because we need so much of it
for everything. And there whenever you
come up with oh I guess there there will
be enough compute because we've reached
this point and you realize no the world
models and everything else and then when
you hear how much more compute I just
think that the part and it was probably
that I heard speak recently uh who
you've had on a bunch of times and I
know you know well where he was a little
bit more concerned uh and I don't know
how much of this was the book he wrote
and how much is actually what he
believes Humanoids are going to take
some time and they're the ones that I
focus a lot of the attention on. Yes, I
know we will have humanoids. Yes, I know
by 2030 they might be more than is in my
head now. But before they're driving
their own car to the delivery before all
of these things, politicians and human
beings have to get comfortable with
this. And full self-driving is already
here, but it's not accepted. You don't
see these cars on the road. And that
should be the easiest one. That argument
of less people will die should be
enough. But because of that, I don't
know how humanoids don't take a a lot
longer to be integrated into society.
>> Yeah. And if you think about how long
it's taken Elon to train the cars to do
what they do.
>> Yep. and he's got to get Optimus out.
And yes, there's, you know, abilities
have increased, but they'll only be
putting specific things first, you know,
on a factory line or in a service center
or whatever it is at first because they
just don't have the compute capacity to
they have the intelligence because
they've got the LLMs, but they don't
have the visual spatial awareness that
they need to navigate the normal world,
the human world. So, they have to be in
restricted environments. They can still
scale massively there, but as you said,
we're a long way from robots walking
down the street, you know, delivering
coffee in humanoid format. It's already
happening in, you know, in other robots.
You see them in streets everywhere now
delivering stuff. So where where I've
started this point is really important
for people to hear when they start
thinking about the concept of PPI and
input costs because I've started to
think more and more about how humanoids
their their most important function over
the next 5 years is going to be in
mines. It's going to be in all parts of
dangerous jobs related to manufacturing.
There's no doubt about it. Um China's
already doing this. if you go look up
mining and the reason I was doing this
is because when I get in discussions and
people go gold or bitcoin I go bitcoin
every single time and they go well you
but you believe in gold and I went you
didn't ask me that if you ask me what I
think will outperform it's because and
actually one of the most famous macro
investors we got into a long discussion
about this in the last 48 hours so my
video came out he wanted to talk about
bitcoin he wanted to talk about
tokenization but then it migrated and I
said but don't you understand that if we
can find more gold and get it easier
because of humanoids, then the capacity
of gold goes up. The reason I'm more
interested in Bitcoin is because it's
chosen by human beings like gold.
There's a community of people that
believe in it, but it's the digital side
and there's a scarcity element to it
that is real. He wanted to talk about
the disruption of hacking and things
like that. And I got him to the point of
AI will hack everything that your brain
can think of, including gold. It will
hack it. it already has hacked it at
CERN. It's only a question of can we get
enough hacking in there to actually
change the ability of the supply side of
anything. And he agreed by the time the
end that you can't pick one and say AI
is going to hack this but not hack
something else. So I think humanoids is
going to have a bigger impact on the
input cost of commodities and us getting
us closer to abundance of cheaper
commodities. So, I I've started to
believe, especially with things like oil
and copper and all of these things,
people might be underestimating how
we're we're going to grow in these, but
I don't think it's ever going to go
parabolic. So, a quick break in your
regular programming. If you're serious
about your future, grab my free report
called Prepare for 2030. I think you've
got 5 years to make as much money as
possible, and this guide will help you
navigate what's coming. The link is in
the description. Download it now. So
let's just go back to the bottleneck of
energy because this is something we all
need to think through. I agree with you.
One of the things I think we have a we
might have talked about this before an
extended or super cycle here is because
you can't have the excess because you
can't build the data centers fast
enough. And then you got this the
political weird slant in the US that
people don't want a data center. I don't
know what they think data centers are
apart from just [\h__\h] buildings. I
mean, it's the it's the weirdest thing.
So, I'd love to hear about the energy
bottleneck and the US political slant to
all of this, which I just can't get my
head around.
So I my head has gotten to the point on
this that I'm less I've become much less
worried about the the data center side
in terms of it being a political issue
because it has forced just like um with
China the way deep sea came out of uh
innovation I don't think people give
enough credit to how much the behind the
meter innovation has been out of control
in the US for building the data centers
we have more natural gas than we need we
have pipelines in many many locations
that don't have to deal with the the
data centers. So I think a lot of these
issues are because data centers were
going to be built in places that we're
probably more vulnerable to this and
since that time since when you start and
announce a data center and you're going
to do it somewhere near a town um and it
takes a year to get going and go through
all the well since then with Colossus
and all of the behind the meter
solutions that have come out I just
think whether it's taking turbines from
old airplanes and then turning them into
gas turbine whatever the case is the
innovation has been through the roof and
so I think we've solved let's say the
the ultimate problem which is we just
move to areas that are better. Um the
demand for it still grows exponentially
but that fits back into the problem of
if it was able to be built we'd have
more data centers being built right now
without the bottlenecks of turbines and
all these problems. So again I'm going
to air on the side that we don't want it
to go too fast. We we I I just think it
would be a much bigger negative for the
capital markets. Then you'd really see
the pressure on the bond market. Um I
think too much too soon is probably a
bad thing and we'd probably get an
overbuild. So I'm going to view the data
centers again the friction as being a
positive.
>> Yeah, I'm of the same route there. So
what else are you looking at right now?
What talk when you let's go back to the
tokenization conversation jumping around
a bit. So you initially when you came
into crypto was very you were very
focused on Bitcoin and you know once it
becomes understandable it's a very
>> logical asset. Now when you're seeing
through the world of tokenization
where's your head going to here
>> in what that future world looks like
because I think that's important because
a lot of people don't understand this
because it used to be a world where
there were like competing things and
that they're not really anymore.
No, I I this this journey um and I get I
think starting as a as a let's say a
Bitcoin as an asset and a maxi type
person and just not believing in uh at
the time in the innovation side and I I
still have that belief that if you ask
me over the next 20 years what am I most
certain of it's that Bitcoin will still
be here and it will be the best asset. I
don't know if any of the other tokens
will still be growing at that point in
value, but there will be innovations
along the way. And that's what I've kind
of come to the conclusion of, and this
goes for public equities as well. So,
where I've got with tokenization is just
the importance of it. I spoke at the New
York Stock Exchange uh to just a
grouping of Korean brokers, retail, like
a hundred of them that were there.
Tokenization is real. It's going to
happen. And it is a race. And this is
one of the things that I recognize that
I don't hear enough people talk about.
We all hear about AI as a race and the
pressure it's putting on, but I don't
think people realize that tokenization
and having it in your country, having
everything on chain is going to become
more critical. So, if you're lagging and
you're not onchain and your assets are
not there, it hurts your market. It
hurts the ability for people to buy it
because they're going to be using their
wallet. This stuff is all going to
happen. It's much cheaper to do. They
can invest quickly. the programmable
nature of it has become something that
I've spent enough time on and just
realized the value of it from so many
different things, how it should be. So
when I've thought about just what a
portfolio will look like and the merging
of the way old school public equities
and debt is with tokenization, the fact
that to actually get to tokenization of
real world assets, you actually had to
get tokenization first of the cash and
collateral, you needed money market
funds, you needed treasury. So you kind
of go through the evolution and you
realize, whoa, we're there. and some of
the new products. And I think this is
because of Robin Hood in particular. I
just think Robin Hood is a perfect place
for the merging of what's kind of crypto
and not kind of crypto. I think they're
a perfect middle ground to have the
community. They have a I don't know if
you've been to any of their events. They
have a strong community. Like people
love their community and people love the
real vision real vision community. Like
communities are really important, but
having a community where their chain is
growing rapidly on the tokenization side
in a short amount of time and you're
seeing those volumes. I just think
people are underestimating the
importance of globally people wanting to
trade 247 hoping that liquidity is
around the clock and that it is being
and I think this is all part of the way
the world is going to be. So I have been
um completely taken taken back by it.
Uh, and the questions I'm now getting
asked by macro people are really good
ones. What happens to the dollar in
tokenization? Like that question. I
don't know if you've thought about it.
It's a great question to have.
>> I wanted to raise Let's talk about this
for a bit because where my head is at
with all of this is there's one country
has the most attractive assets in the
world right now. It's the United States.
The moment you put it on chain, the
equity market, it just attracts even
more capital. It crowds everybody out.
And the dollar is the same because the
dollar now goes to the end of the line
to the individual when it had to go
through the euro dollar markets before
that's all gone. So, you know, if I
think when people talk about the the
collapse of the dollar, whatever, my
view has been and the same with Brent
Johnson is that it dies of its own of
its strength because if you do that, the
dollar will be so strong. It's already
been strong over the last decade and a
half over time, just cyclical. Um, but
if you're going to get every investor
because why would you bother to invest
in you know some European you know
whatever it is kind packaging company
when you can buy Nvidia it's like it's
very hard or SpaceX it's very hard not
to attract all of the capital.
So I although I agree from a so I've
broken this down into two parts. you're
you're bringing up the transaction part
and the um if people have to invest the
the issue is right now uh 75% of the
investing dollars of the world via MSCI
world are in the US already so from an
equity basis they're already there I
have viewed um public equities as being
an issue relative to entrepreneurs so 10
years from now I don't think US equities
the growth perspective is going to be
the same that way people see them now. I
I think entrepreneurs around the globe
who use AI of which countries that are
poorer in my opinion are adopting AI
faster. Um they're using AI faster and
the reason is because
>> they want to and they have to. And so I
know you you remember this. I have
viewed the AXI Infinity example
>> as something everyone needs to go study
and just realize that that that example
of how an economy grows virtually. Um,
people need to think about that with
tokenization in my opinion because I I
just I studied that. That's what re
originally got me so interested in in
crypto the ecosystem was what was
happening with Daxi Infinity. The other
part of the dollar is control. So from a
geopolitical basis, tokenization and all
these things, I think the control goes
down because of stable coins and all
this. So I agree that there's a positive
force of the dollar. I think there's a
negative force which is the more that
everything goes on chain the less
control the US has over swift the less
the US has control over sanctions and
then it just becomes something where
over time there's no such thing as a
collapse I view everything as dollars
will migrate and distribute around the
globe and it'll take a while for
entrepreneurs to compete with Google but
they will they'll compete with everyone
so it's a gradual kind of growing of the
private entrepreneur market and a
shrinking of the enterprise market
>> it's the old trend of bundling,
unbundling, centralization,
decentralization.
>> And that's what's happened. I mean, look
at what you and I are doing ourselves
with AI. We would have hired a company
to build these things for us. It would
have taken us 6 months, 9 months. It
wouldn't been perfect. And then and now
we're just doing it on the fly. And
that's showing you the direction of
travel is that the the the centralized
approach in everything is about to go.
Now, there's going to be some
centralized players. I mean, good luck
trying to disrupt SpaceX, but you know.
[laughter]
>> Yes. But I I agree with you. I I think
um AI and and crypto, those are the two
most powerful parts of it is they're
they are truly decentralizing. They are
borderless. It allows people to not
think about things the way that we all
think about them because of the way we
grow grew up. And I already think kids
are down that path because of the way
things have been with video games, the
way things were with every single part
of kind of the growth of crypto in 2021
and 2022 during COVID. We will all look
back on that as the beginning of really
this move into the virtual world for the
younger generation in a very big way
into crypto. I know with my son that's
when he first got into it and it drove
me into it because I didn't think the
metaverse made sense other than the fact
that I watched him play video games and
he was already in the metaverse in 2016
um and this was just another extension
of it. So we forgot all those things. I
know you're heavy into NFTTS. NFTs fit
into that as well. I just think that um
it will take some change. But the one
thing that has always lasted with all
human beings regardless of their age at
the end of the day if nothing is growing
except for the digital world and people
will invest in the digital world. That's
it. Like it if if you want growth in
investing that's where you'll be. So I I
tell you I just I was just thinking this
morning was a great example of how the
world has changed so much. So I've built
this kind of huge GMI portal within Real
Vision that has charts and analysis and
AI compression to make sense of it all
all of this stuff and you know across
the different tiers and my AI checks the
inbox the bugs at
globalmicroinvestor.com
and it pinged me this morning said a
couple of really good ideas in there um
that um people should be able to go
around all these dashboards and tick
their favorite charts and it should
create a new page with their favorite
charts and whatever. I said it's a great
idea. let's build it. And I from getting
that email to shipping it to everybody
was 40 minutes of which I wasn't doing
anything apart from occasionally talking
into my whisper and it's launched on
real vision and I'm like holy [\h__\h]
Imagine what that would be like before.
You'd have to call up the company. You'd
have to have meetings with them. You
know, I want to develop this. they come
back and you dis I mean the collapse in
time and cost of developing stuff is
stupid.
>> Yeah. and obviously uh learning and
that's really been my that's been my big
thing has been how quickly I can learn a
particular topic because of YouTube
because of uh the ability of going into
X and now not having to search and not
know what's there but actually going to
go and say give me the best posts on
this particular topic and have it give
it to me using and creating a knowledge
brain and connecting into the YouTube
API and creating the last 20 um video
transcripts of Jensen Yuang or of Raul
Pal or whomever and then to really get
through this it has gotten to the point
where since I launched my subscriber
side and I get so many questions
>> I don't want to give people the answers
I want to give them basically the
ability of doing it themselves and so my
my thought has been empowerment and with
Grockbot it hit me so hard when I
started to use it and so this you know
the past week I'd had so many people
reach out after a video where I showed
them all my agents like should
[clears throat] I really get started?
And I literally said, "Here's the deal,
guys. I'm going to give you a five-page
thing that all you have to do is
literally paste this into Grockbot. You
will have your chief of staff. You will
have different components of it. He will
set up all the agents and then you can
just start conversing. And all you got
to do is copy paste, copy paste, copy
paste, let it go through its thing. And
by having the ability of having a
YouTube that gets enough people, having
subscribers and getting through it, your
your point's valid. It's like I I'm
trying to empower people to make sure
they use AI and to feel like they're
growing, but the ability of not only
giving them answers, giving them
homework to do on their own and then
realizing that the amount of people have
reached out saying, "I never thought I
could do any of this type of stuff." You
know how empowering because I remember
when you came to my office and you asked
me a question about how I was using it
and you're like, "Oh my god, we I got to
do that, too." And we were kind of
exchanging information on how we were
using it. So having a community
community of of empowered users is just
great.
Yeah. And but so many people have this
fear barrier. It's like and Grockbot is
really good because you can just in very
natural language say, "Hey, read my X
feed and tell me what I've missed on AI
every day and give me a summary." And it
just does it. You don't It just says,
"Oh, do you want me to connect to this?"
And you go, "Yes, yes, yes. Done." You
don't have to do anything. No, it's um
it it as far as I'm concerned um other
than see chat GBT all you had to do was
kind of do what you did in Google search
and it didn't take much learning.
this this situation where you recognize
the power of having people working for
you and being able to say, "Hey, put
together the newspaper for me of what I
care about and have it ready for me at 5
in the morning, which I have it do for
me in crypto." And then I give it the
websites that I wanted to go search on
and just give me the most important
things, match them up with X, and make
sure these are trending stories as well.
Like I don't think people realize that
like customizing the news that you want
have it delivered to you from overnight.
It's just a very powerful thing to be
able to do using something like that
where
>> and that's one of the most simple things
to do now.
>> Exactly.
>> It's really not it's really not that
complicated. But how do you deal with we
we briefly touched on this in the
beginning. How do you deal with all of
having all of the agents and all of the
scheduled tasks and all of the things?
cuz I find if I'm not careful, it's like
two hours of my morning is fixing [\h__\h]
that didn't happen. The Google Drive
connector went down, this happened, and
then I've spent the last two days
working with my COO to go and
automatically fix all this stuff. And
then that doesn't it's like it's not
it's not simple all the time.
>> Well, Open Claw was what you described
to me was what I went through with
OpenClaw. Eventually, Hermes exact same
thing. So whenever anyone says this is
perfect, it it was never perfect ever.
Um you had to deal with errors that
would pop up and you did have to deal
with your computer, you know, and true
story, uh cleaning lady comes over and
[laughter] closes my my my
laptop and all of a sudden I'm like,
"Wait, where's my agent?" And I'm like
asking him, there's nothing going on and
I I can't get anything. Now I don't have
to deal with that with Grockbot. And so
it still makes errors, but I've only
been using it for less than whatever 3
weeks. And it's not perfect. But I will
tell you the ability of going in and
signing into my actual log on on Twitter
and it being able to go through my lists
of stuff is very powerful to do that
with anything that I want software-wise
and have it on a virtual computer that
it's going in. It does a lot of things
where I think the more important thing
is the getting used to it, knowing how
to use it, what it can be good for, and
that way when it actually gets better,
which you know it will in a year from
now it'll be completely different than
it is today. You [snorts] have to
develop the brain set of knowing how
you'd use it.
>> Yeah. But now I've got the problem is
I've got agents on Grockbot, agents on
Hermes, agents on Claude,
you know, and now I need an COO across
all of my a [laughter]
I've migrated some of my stuff over
already, but I don't think I went as far
into it as as you did. Um, I I will tell
you one of the best things that I used
them for is something that I is very
similar to my days at Morgan Stanley and
at the hedge fund, which was using them
as a team of people, calling a meeting.
We all get together. I tell the chief of
staff, "Let's get together. I have this
problem that I want to solve for." And I
had a situation last week where the way
that I did my videos, um, the company
that the software I used basically said
they were going out of business on a
Wednesday. Now, I do my video recording
on a Friday. So,
I had to put this together in a
completely different way. So, I called a
staff meeting and I went in a Grockpot
and I literally went through it and I
said, "All right, how are we going to
solve this problem? What's the best way
to get through it?" And I'm telling you,
Row, it was literally like being a
Morgan Stanley, being a managing
director, having everyone come into the
room. We got a problem to solve. Let's
solve it. And we got to the point and
literally it was, okay, you should use
Google Slides to do it, which is what I
did, ended up doing over the weekend.
And in the end, when I asked them, okay,
is this going to save me time? And they
said, it'll definitely save you time.
Now, along the way to learn Google
Slides, so it's one thing for them to
say, you should use Google Slides. Well,
if it's not something I use all the
time, I needed them to help me along the
way of, okay, will you make sure you're
on top of this? Who's the expert on
Google Slides? And so that agent I
worked with one by one by one until I
was able to do it. And it took me, I
want to say, a few hours to honestly not
be an expert at Google Slides, but now I
can do a 100 video slide video. And I
was able to do that switch over from a a
Wednesday to a Thursday morning. And you
know how stressful that type of stuff
can be when you're wanting to get
something done that you do regularly. So
>> it's just it's a it's amazing.
I've had many people now ask me I wrote
about in GMI actually. I'm like this is
what I'm using AI for and this is what
I've built and I'm in the middle of
building and people are like holy [\h__\h]
I'm like yeah it's a lot. It's a lot.
Now I got a question for you. How many
people do you meet?
because we're right around the same age,
our age. So, straddling the 60 uh area
that are not
technology people like I always had
people working for me. You had people
working for me. You didn't need to be an
expert. How many people do you meet our
age non-technology people that you see
using it as actively and in the ways
that we are?
>> Zero.
>> They have to be running a business
even then.
>> Yeah, you're right. Think of your
friends.
>> Yeah.
>> Your kind of the people you grew up
with, not friends that you know from X
and this world, but
>> even when you go to your trading friends
and people who work at hedge funds, they
might have an analyst who's using AI to
do stuff. Nobody's doing what we're
doing. But then everybody, the other
group around me, everybody's doing this.
But in in the world, in the traditional
world, they're not.
It's like it's really weird.
>> I it's it's impossible for me to
describe and and so
my business so we've been talking like
every 3 months. So I launched my
subscriber side in February of this year
and the amount of things I put up every
week.
>> Is that all? It feels like it's much
longer.
>> No. Well, the YouTube started two years
ago. That's right.
>> I didn't actually start a subscriber
wall until February. And what has
happened and this is the most
unbelievable thing it forget forget the
growth in the community that's great and
I appreciate everyone doing I'm more how
much work I do a week that gets uploaded
to there for them it's anywhere from
7 to 12 things a week that I build I
upload in there these are from code that
I write or have built for me they're
ideas that I come up with I'm starting a
crypto portion that will be part of the
site as of the end of this month. And
that's why I'm spending so much time on
tokenization and I'm built I built out
um and and you I don't know if you've
done this. I I I have talked to Jamie a
bunch of times. We've conver you know um
shared information on this but my whole
belief has been that if you take an
equal weight of the ecosystem of the
best
tokens covering a diversified in my case
10 sectors with inside crypto and you
put in any public stocks like circle I
even have Robin Hood I have PayPal into
this into the different verticals of the
merging
the correlation between that equal wake
basket with Bitcoin is close to one
there's not much difference when you go
through it. And the reason I wanted to
do that is I've said to people, you have
to understand from my perspective, the
S&P 500 is this amorphous thing. It it
doesn't mean anything. It it has
innovation that gets rid of the losers
and keeps the winners and it changes.
And if you believe in hyper competition
and hyper speed, that means growth
companies will be leaving it faster than
they've ever left it before because you
will be disrupted. You will be moved
out. And we've obviously seen that fears
over um the software names and you've
seen it even with anthropic and people
get worried that their AR has stalled
and I do believe that we're in this
hyperco competitive world. So my endgame
has always been the same which is what
Bitcoin ends up representing is the only
true scarcity thing of a store of value.
So if you're make if your job investing
is to pick things that are growing and
then they stop growing your job is to
get rid of that and find the next
grower. Well, while you're looking for
the next grower, you need to put your
money into a store of value. So, Bitcoin
theoretically should equal all of that.
And it does. And that's what makes me
feel good. And that's what again brings
me back to the point of when you're
using AI and you're on top of how fast
the world is changing. And that Bitcoin
is directly related to the disruption
from AI. It's related to the fact that
in a world of abundance, you need to
find things that are truly scarce that
people believe in. And there's not many
things that are truly scarce that people
believe in. There's plenty of things
that are scarce right now, but I don't
believe they'll be scarce in the future.
And that's where it always ends up as
Bitcoin ends up being here. And along
the way, we pick and choose innovations
that we think are going to do well. I
think Ethereum will outperform Bitcoin
over the next year because of the
tokenization boom and the stable coin
boom and what we said about the volume,
the velocity, and people understanding
theoretically Ethereum is a commodity
related to the blockchain. And if
there's only a certain amount of places,
we're going to run into compute. And so
I've kind of said to people, it's not a
direct relationship, but I view Ethereum
because of the trust factor of this
merge. And I'd like to hear your because
I know you've been into other into
Salana in Suie and other places that
have gone through. My my belief has been
that for the banks and all these people,
Ethereum because of its size, because of
the time it's been there and because of
how difficult it is for people to trust
something new, that the trust factor is
going to be a very important part of the
financial guard rails. And so I've
started to accept the fact that I want
to be in on top of the innovation
related to tokenization. I want to be on
top of what's going to happen. But
that's where I've kind of gotten to with
this whole subscriber thing on this.
>> I think we spend far too much time,
everybody, in choosing stuff to buy and
sell.
>> Agreed.
>> Really, you could own
Bitcoin,
the NASDAQ,
and probably do nothing else and you'll
be fine,
>> right? Well, if you want to own a bit of
gold, but you got, you know, it doesn't
really matter because it's, you know,
Bitcoin does roughly the same kind of
thing. But, you know, that's all you
need to actually do and you never need
to turn on your screen again. And in
crypto, I've got it down very simply is
obviously Bitcoin.
Um, I also like the Zcash
privacy narrative. So, you have a little
bit of that and a big bit of that. Okay,
fine. But then you've got the whole
smart contract layer, and that doesn't
represent it at all. They're correlated,
but they're not the same thing. And
simply, I just used cloud
and other big networks and said, well,
there's generally
four or five that are dominant and one
is more dominant than others. And so,
you just look at that and say, okay,
well, what are they? Well, the two clear
ones right now are Ethereum and Salana.
And then you've got others and let's
see. Hyperlquid's different because it's
it's sort of more of a business built on
blockchain. Um, and a lot of the others
are businesses built on the technology.
You know, what did cloud enable? What
did all of these things enable? Um, and
that's a harder bet right now because
we're still early in the infrastructure
bet. So, that's all I just think is like
you just buy a basket of, you know,
three to five smart contract chains. You
can even market cap weight them for now.
It's fine. And a bit of Bitcoin and a
bit of Zcash and you just don't have to
do anything. Or the other level of the
portfolio is you just buy some NASDAQ,
buy some Bitcoin, buy some ETH, buy some
gold and and just don't do anything else
for a long time. It's just and we yet we
write so much and people want dashboards
and business cycles and technical
analysis and all of this stuff and
actually you don't really need to.
>> You weren't going to say stuff. I know
what you're going to say.
>> [laughter]
>> Um, so wait, let's go let's go back then
because another common
>> by your face you're like, "Yeah, it's
true." Um, [laughter]
we uh we both love studying the human
brain. We both love understanding um
psychology, consciousness. So let's go
back to what you said at the beginning.
Why do you think people do this? Because
I agree with you that it's completely
unnecessary. So why do you think people
do it? I have my own thoughts. I
it's a sense of control of agency. It's
like you have some control over your
financial future. If you have a set it
and forget it portfolio, it's like you
have no control. It just does it. And
yes, it probably works. Um but people
feel like
they feel a desperate need to get ahead.
And we've talked about this before. You
know, speculation, prediction markets,
sports betting, it's all part of the
same trend, which is people don't have
enough money. debasement of currencies
kind of screwed people over and they
want to take control. So, but people
turn themselves into knots over this
stuff. I mean, I see it on the real
vision platform, you know, that
desperately searching for a guru or a
system or a product or a something and
it's like it doesn't exist, guys. It's
like the markets are an amalgamation of
all of us and that's what's in the
price. Bizarrely
>> I so I think um
>> I doesn't mean to say you can't
outperform or under you know all of that
stuff you know the GMI track record is
you know one of the best there's been
but because that's time horizon really
but yeah I don't know there's just some
horrible truth to all of this
>> so the reason people are willing to put
100% of their money in
>> it also doesn't sell newsletters
>> correct [laughter] that is true well
See, now we're getting to the different
side. I'm more So, I've thought about
why people complain and I live in
Williamsburg. I see the building chat.
Everyone complains. Everyone in this
this place voted for Mandani. Like, it's
it's a it's a unique place. So, they
vote for Mandani. They complain about
how expensive things are, but then I see
them all traveling to the Hamptons, and
I see them all going on flights, and I
see them all spending money. So there's
some disconnect because they say they're
poor, but they live in a building that
costs a lot of money and they're
traveling all over the place. So I've
kind of come to the belief that people
are all looking for the next big thing
and it's this hope that they found
something that no one else found and
they're going to make money and go
through it because nobody the S&P 500
you're investing in 500 companies. So if
you put all of your money in the S&P
500, you've invested in 500 companies.
But if someone said, "I have all my
money in the S&P 500." Like, "Well, you
should put more in the NASDAQ. You
should put it here." And by the time
you're done, it's like, "Well, you've
diversified into such a level." But if
you say, "I've invested all my money in
Bitcoin." People think you're crazy.
>> And the reason is because it can it will
be gone. And I view it as being all
things, but it's compounded.
You don't need the next big thing. Like,
it's compounded. To your point, NASDAQ,
same thing. Why are you searching to
compound at a higher level than two
things that if you did them 50/50 have
compounded at such a high level? If you
make it a third, a third, a third with
the S&P 500. Guys, since the Bitcoin
white paper, you don't need to do
anything else. You're outperforming
everything that needs to happen. I just
think people are never happy. And I
think we're in this world where it's
kind of playing out where the you're
fighting you're you're going upstream
because you're comparing yourself to
people that have made so much money and
it's in this world of assets going to
the level they are $180 trillion in the
US of net worth. I think it's this
mystical thing that people believe
they're going to they're going to get
into that 180 trillion by just buying
something at a penny that'll go up to a
thousand. It's just not going to happen.
And I think they should just compound in
in the things that work like you.
>> Yeah. And focus on increasing your
income.
>> Exactly.
>> That's the thing that actually makes the
difference because you have more ability
to invest. You can dollar cost average.
You can compound over time. People
forget that bit. If you if you figure a
way to just take the compounding and you
take the NASDAQ, S&P, and Bitcoin since
the white paper came out and you do a
third, a third, a third, and you just go
through and you're like, "Okay, here's
the compounding number and let's assume
by going through that it's 33%." And
you're like, "Okay, if I compounded
33%," and you go, "Okay, now go do your
income. compound it at 33% and see where
you'll be in in in 20 years just by
taking 20% of that income 15% of that
income letting it grow and always taking
15% you'll be shocked at how much money
you have in 20 years. So here so here's
a question of our theoretical
idiot proof portfolio do you rebalance
because if not you've got 97 98% Bitcoin
[laughter]
and I don't believe in rebalancing but
you've got no diversification now at all
so the NASDAQ can outperform for five
years and not move the dial at all
Bitcoin returns I don't know how to
think about that
>> I so when people have asked me and and I
Guess now that I'm I've been a part of
the community long enough.
I've never sold a Bitcoin. I've never
sold anything in it. And it's just
amazing. I You haven't either?
>> No. I
>> I mean, I've sold I've switched, but
I've never taken money out of digital
assets
>> ever. I've never I've never had a
transaction that brings money back into
the bank.
>> It It's always a bigger number. And part
of it is appreciation, but part of it is
as I get more money and I don't I don't
need to buy anything else in my life. So
I have what I want. Everything is to me
about a trip that I want to take or this
and that. So I'm one of the lucky people
that's made enough money in life where I
don't need to go out and spend money.
I'm I'm not buying more. I I own I own a
home in Maine. That's it. Like that's
it. I don't need anything. I have a
Tesla from 2021. I'm just not a spender.
I never have been. I just don't care.
I have no interest in rebalancing
because I don't need to and I'm not
thinking about it in that way and I do
view it as if that money continues to
grow that's a better life for my kids or
a better life for me giving away or
whatever the case is down the road but
it's something I believe in and I've I
rode a Substack which I still believe I
was trained at the racetrack by my
father I started going to the racetrack
according to my mother before I can way
before I can remember but from the time
that I can remember, which must be, you
know, four to five years old. He was
teaching me how to handicap a horse
race. And I wrote this Substack about
the greatest odds I've ever seen on
something and the building of the
digital asset rails, the belief that AI
will disrupt the fiat system and that
more and more people will migrate that
money over to here, which you believe in
and I believe in. And it's funny, I
heard you say because I get asked the
question all the time, so what's your
price on Bitcoin? And I go, okay, I'm
not going to do this anymore, but here's
what I will do. I think the size of the
digital asset world will be at least
hundred trillion. And I do that not as
like a random starting point, but if
it's 700 trillion on one side of the
equation and I believe that that money
is going to grow over there and it'll be
a combination of that side either not
growing or going down to some degree and
this side growing it it has to get to
that level. There's no other way that it
that that can happen. There's it's the
digital economy and it has to grow that
way. So when you get back to it and I
go, well then what do you think? I'm
like, well, then it gets back to how
much you think Bitcoin will be as a
percentage of that number. And if I say
it'll never go below 33%, which is what
I believe, then I can come up with a
number that I can make an argument
towards. Um, that's the way I think
about this whole thing and kind of the
migrate. And it's always funny that you
and I um trained in a similar way,
thinking of markets in a macro
perspective, completely different in
terms of the way we kind of I'd say get
to the end game. We end up with similar
numbers.
But the the thing I think we both
appreciate the most is, you know, the
most exciting time of our entire career
is now. And we've gone through all
sorts. We've seen some really amazing
stuff. And now it's like this is I mean
the most
concentrated you've ever had to be.
Diversification kind of means nothing at
this. And it's the most exciting time to
be alive and to be part of this is
amazing. and to help people in their
journey as well of this is really
special. Can
>> can can you imagine um if you would have
said five years ago the S&P will be
growing uh 33% job hiring will be zero.
Profit margins will be going parabolic
not just in the US but globally.
We'd be having a cancer vaccine come
out. we'd be you can go through
>> talk about that
>> and
people would be worried about whether 10
year yields are five and three/4ers or
5.8% or 5.9%. Like I just I think the
social media world I think the it's too
good it can't possibly be this good. I
didn't think I would feel this good at
I'm going to be 60 years old in March. I
didn't think I'd feel this good at this
age. I didn't think I'd be able to work
out every single day and think about
anti-aging and going through this. So I
just I'm I I agree with you. It's the
best time, the most enjoyable time, and
I'm learning more than I've ever learned
in my life. So, I feel younger in almost
every way I can possibly be younger.
>> Fantastic, Jordi. As ever, my friend,
fantastic conversation, and I always
look forward to our next one.
>> Same here, Raul. Get get Nappa.
>> And don't forget to pre-order my book,
>> of course. What's the name of it?
>> The Everything Code, because it's
actually written with AI. It's the first
major book that a major publisher, so
it's Pam McMillan. um and Haramman
House, they trained their AI on all of
my content and I gave them content and
then they built the narrative of the
book and I helped craft it with the
editor.
>> But it was it collapsed the the time to
write a proper book from you, however
long to, you know, a much shorter period
of time. It's been an amazing thing. So
anyway, so they
>> you're not worried you're not worried
about the Wall Street Journal and and
and the drug uh AI oped fiasco. You're
not worried about that. At least you're
disclosing it. So
>> well, the whole thing is disclosed as
this is the first book ever done this
way [laughter]
>> and it's written by me. It's all my
content and you know crafted. But yeah,
it's it's let's see how it goes down. Be
interesting. But it's the first one.
>> I'm looking forward to it. I obviously
have seen the everything code. I I've
probably listened to more podcasts with
you talking about it and I I believe
that hearing this hearing a person talk
about the same thing multiple times, I
always absorb more because there's
something either I missed or something
that went through. So, I will certainly
get the book. [laughter]
>> All right, my friend. Well, good to see
you as ever and I'll see you soon.
>> See you soon.
>> Well, another great conversation with
Jordi. Now remember, if you want to
carry on the conversation with me about
any of my content, any of the videos,
any of the conversations, or my
investing frameworks, just go to
ralpal.ai and you can talk to me in my
own voice and that's trained on all of
the information that will help you in
your journey. So see you there. Token
2049 Singapore, the world's largest
crypto event, returns to Marina Bay
Sands on the 7th of 8th of October. On
stage will be myself, Jeff Yan from
Hyperlquid, Shane Copam from Poly
Market, and the Real Vision community
gets 10% off tickets. Claim yours using
the link below. See you there. So, you
obviously like this video enough that
you've got to the end. That's quite a
big task, but listen, do me a favor. Hit
the like and subscribe button and also
check out what videos next because I
think you'll love it. But if you want
even more, and when I'm talking more,
I'm talking about memberergenerated
ideas, incredible alpha research,
everything there to help you in your
journey, just head to realton.com/join
for the best financial intelligence out
there and the pure alpha that's within
the platform.